Andrew A Hamlin

860-810-6538 | aahamlin@gmail.com | 15 North Drive, Simsbury, CT

Profile

A servant leader with 20 years of software engineering experience throughout the software development life cycle including Agile release planning and execution, software development, cloud architecture, test-driven development, automation, systems integration, global workforce management, recruitment, and onboarding.

Earned an *Employee Recognition Award* for raising customer satisfaction scores, measured by KLAS, by transforming Sustaining Engineering operations.

Relevant Skills

- Leadership and care of software engineers
- Collaboration and consensus building among cross functional teams
- Global workforce management including hiring and onboarding
- Stewardship of standards and best practices throughout the SDLC

Experience

Gerber Technology, LLC: Tolland, CT ------ 2018-2019

Sr Software Development Manager

Introduced best practices, such as technical design, CI/CD (Jenkins), and code review that resulted in 86% decrease in defects. Educated cross-functional teams (approx. 50 people) on Agile release planning methods, such as Sprint Backlogs, Epic/Story development, and supported its implementation while transitioning from 1-yr to 3-mo release cycles. Initiated and facilitated architecture and refactoring initiatives to address deficiencies in legacy code base. Met regularly to support 8 direct reports in areas including process changes, performance management and conflict resolution. Managed 20 offshore contract resources.

Sailpoint Technologies: Austin, TX ------ 2017-2018

Software Development Manager

Scrum master of two 6-8 person scrum teams, accountable for design, development and validation of Enterprise IAM features in Java, SQL and Angular.js such as Multi-factor authentication (MFA), OAuth, REST APIs, and Accessibility. Contributed to best practices in code reviews, test coverage, documentation, security and localization. Automated sprint reporting in Python. Coached and evaluated direct reports in various career stages and functional areas.

Caradigm USA, LLC: Remote ------2012-2016

Software Development Manager & Team Lead: 2013 - 2016

Led 8-person team implementing a Governance, Risk and Compliance (GRC) platform including single page app (SPA) UI and data warehouse functionality, implemented in C#, WebAPI (REST), SQL, HTML/CSS, Javascript (Knockout.js). Led badge reader integration of Linux VDI thin clients and SSO platform in Python, C, and Java. Envisioned, designed and won support for development of CI/CD pipeline with gated-checkins and end-to-end test automation system, then coached team members on its adoption and use. Developed interviewing and onboarding standards and documentation.

Sustaining Engineering Manager: 2012 - 2013

Established and owned prioritization process and service level agreements with customer support, professional service and pre-sales teams. Drove 6-month turn around of operations utilizing Kanban and met 100% of our SLAs. Resolved scalability and performance of custom network load balancer software. Developed engineers skills and self-reliance through mentorships, training and 1:1 support. Earned *Employee Recognition Award*. Managed 10-person on/offshore team including contract resources.

Microsoft Corporation: Remote ------ 2010-2012

Software Development Engineer II

Led transition to Windows tech stack (C#/.NET, WCF, PowerShell) and service-based architecture through discovery and self-learning then teaching and coaching of 6-person team. Integrated a dependency injection library that enabled universal logging and implementation of integration test suites across distributed services and desktop apps. Co-developed self-contained polyglot build system incl. static code analysis and test coverage used by 40 developers.

Sentillion, Inc: Andover, MA ------ 1999-2010

Senior Software Engineer

Developed Enterprise Identity Access Management (IAM) and Single Sign-on (SSO) solution for Windows and Linux servers, primarily written in Java and Perl; a *KLAS Top 20 Product*. Eliminated licensing costs by replacing high-availability software with open source alternatives.

Education

Daniel Webster College: Nashua, NH

BS Management and Information Technology